101cookingfortwo.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy | 101 Cooking For Two

#### **Effective as of May 24, 2018**

As the owner of this website (the “Site”),  101 Cooking For Two LLC, we understand that your privacy is of critical importance.  This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect from you via the Site and how we use and disclose such information.

###  **Our Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;

(b) advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you as outlined in the Advertising Privacy Statement of this document; and

(c) analysis – we use cookies [to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services;

###  **Web Analysis**

We use **Google Analytics** to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. We at 101 Cooking for Two have “privatized” the data collected by Google by eliminating part of the IP address which should help prevent personal identification.

This site, 101 Cooking for Two, also uses **StatCounter** for further analysis of site activities to help improve the site experience for site visitors.

Statcounter is an online service which helps us to understand our visitors; for example, how visitors find our website, how long they spend on our site, which web pages they are most interested in etc. We use Statcounter because better understanding how visitors are interacting with our website helps us to improve the content, design, and functionality of our site. This allows us to offer a better online experience to our visitors. 

Statcounter uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on visitors and visitor activity on our website. This data includes:

  * The IP address (this is a numerical label assigned to a device by an Internet Service Provider to enable the device to access the internet.) The IP address collected for this purpose have been altered to prevent personal identification by eliminating the last three digits of the IP address.
  * Time and date of visit (this can help us to identify and plan for busy periods on our website)
  * Browser and Operating System (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the browsers/operating systems used to access our site)
  * Device Information e.g. device type and screen size (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the devices used to access our site)
  * Referring Data e.g. a search engine link (this can help us to understand which search engines are helping visitors to find our website)

Furthermore, when you visit our website, a Statcounter cookie (called “is_unique”) may be placed in your browser. This cookie is used only to determine whether you are a first-time or returning visitor and to estimate unique visits to the site.

You can learn more about cookies from StatCounter and set your browser to refuse same by clicking [here](http://statcounter.com/about/set-refusal-cookie/).

For further details, please see the [Statcounter privacy policy](https://statcounter.com/about/legal/#privacy).

###  **Browser Cookies**

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can, however, obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including our Site. Some features of the Site may cease to be available to you.

##  **Interest-Based Advertising**

###  **Advertising Privacy Statement**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser, your opt-out will not be maintained.

 **For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

###  **Email Addresses**

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion. If you have provided your email address to us, we promise to use it only for the purposes for which it is provided.  We will not use your email address to contact you for unrelated reasons. And we will not share your email address with any third parties.

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

###  **Where we send your data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

All data is stored on our host server at Liquid Web, <https://www.liquidweb.com/> , and a backup server owned and operated by Liquid Web. No additional data is being collected by them at our request. You may review their privacy statement at <https://www.liquidweb.com/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/>.

### Cloudflare

Our site is served through Cloudflare. Cloudflare helps our site load faster by storing copies of our content in data centers around the world and defends our site from attacks by logging requests to detect and block suspicious traffic. For more information on how Cloudflare handles the data it collects, see [Cloudflare’s privacy policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

###  **Social Media**

101 Cooking for Two provides connections to various social media outlets to help you share our content. Each of those links to the various social media outlets is governed by their Privacy Policy, and we have no control over that data.

### Embedded content from other sites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

###  **Affiliate Program Participation**

The Site may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Site. If you click on a link to an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

The Site is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Site will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

This site also participates in an affiliate relationship with Thermoworks at [https://www.thermoworks.com](https://www.thermoworks.com/) which, like Amazon, provides customized links. If you click those links, a cookie may be placed in your browser to track referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

###  **Server log files**.

When you use 101 Cooking for Two, our server automatically records certain log file information, including your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, the number of clicks and how you interact with links/pages on the site. This log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you make a request to visit a web page.

The information in the log files is only used to maintain the server and correct problems and errors.

###  **What about other websites 101 Cooking for Two links to?**

From time to time, 101 Cooking for Two will provides links to other websites as a convenience to our visitors. Those sites are not owned by 101 Cooking for Two LLC and are not governed by this privacy policy. We encourage you to review the privacy and security policies of any website that you visit.

### Minors

This website is intended for use by adults 18 years and older. We do not intentionally, nor knowingly, collect personal information from minors without parental consent. If you are under the age of 18, you must cease use of this website immediately.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

### How long do we retain your data?

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you sign up to receive email newsletters – your information is kept indefinitely for the purposes of sending you our email newsletter. You can unsubscribe at any time by hitting the unsubscribe button which is found on the bottom of any email received by us.

####  **ADDITIONAL RIGHTS OF EEA (EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA) RESIDENTS**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i) access your personal data

(ii) ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v) the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

Among other means that you may provide us with our communicating with you, you consent and agree to communicate with us via email.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by contacting us at  
DrDan at 101cookingfortwo dot com.

###  **Sale of Business or Assets**

In the event that the Site or substantially all of its assets is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, the information we have collected about you may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction.

###  **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Site, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using our Site or services after the Effective Date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.

### Agreeing to Terms

If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy as posted here on this website, please do not use this site or any services offered by this site.

Your use of this site indicates acceptance of this privacy policy.

###  **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of this Site, please contact us at DrDan at 101cookingfortwo dot com

Originally Published May 24, 2018

Last Updated May 24, 2018
